so let's see if we know how to add some
prefetch instructions suppose we have a
program like this where I goes from 0 to
1000 and J goes from 0 to 1000 and in
every iteration of this inner loop we
add to the ice element of the a array
the element of the B matrix so what is
really happening here is that in the
first iteration of the outer loop we
will compute a 0 then a 1 and so on and
we do that by basically adding up all
the appropriate elements from the B
array let's say that the elements of the
a and B arrays are both floating-point
numbers that are each 8 bytes in size
let's say that the cache size is 16
kilobytes fully associative with LRU
replacement let's say that a single
iteration of this inner loop takes 10
cycles if there are no misses and that
the miss penalty is 200 cycles because
the memory latency is 200 cycles the
question for you is if we insert a
prefetch instruction here so that we can
prefetch one of the next a elements what
should be the distance here or check
this if we simply should not be doing
this here for prefetching elements of B
in this loop what is the distance at
which we should be prefetching or should
we just not be doing this